(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
YouTube music weekend
Special LIVE
NON-FICTION
皆さん、こんあずき！あずきです！
Hello, everyone! This is AZKi!
今日は一緒に盛り上がっていきましょう！
Let's get hyped together today!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
仄暗い部屋の
In a dimly lit room
片隅で蹲る日々に
In the days spent huddling in a corner
夕焼けが射してる
The sunset is shining
午前二時半少し手前
A little before 2:30 AM
眠気に呑まれて
Swallowed by drowsiness
すべてを諦めてしまえば
If I were to give up on everything
愚か者は皆
All the fools
すぐに忘れ去っていくから
Will soon forget and leave
もう 日が昇ってしまう
Soon, the sun will rise
もう 明日が来てしまう
Soon, tomorrow will come
生きたくないと願った
In the moment I wished
瞬間にさ、ほら、誰かが死ぬ
That I didn't want to live, look, someone dies
分かっていたのに、どうして
I knew that, so why
どうして、どうして
Why, oh why?
世界はこんなにも 回る、回る、回る、回る
The world keeps revolving like this, round and round
目が眩んで おかしくなりそうよ
It's so dazzling, I feel like I'm going crazy
ーもう一度だけー
-Just one more time-
世界はこんなにも 廻る、廻る、廻る、廻る
The world keeps turning like this, again and again
息もできない
I can't even breathe
本当に私、疲れてしまったんだわ
I've really just become so tired
生きることに精一杯になりすぎてた
I was trying so hard just to live
私、今…
And now, I...
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
振り回す姿勢
The posture of waving around
四方にばらまいた感情
Emotions scattered in all directions
いない、ここにはいない
Not here, not in this place
嘘をついて、姿を消して
Telling lies, disappearing from sight
また 幾度繰り返す
Again, repeating over and over
また 後悔が重ねられる
Again, the regrets pile up
ゼロから1やり直し
Starting over from zero to one
生まれ変われば、なんて嘘とか
Lies like 'if I could be reborn'
分かってないのに、どうして
I don't even understand, so why
どうして、どうして
Why, oh why?
夜から朝
From night to morning
冬から夏
From winter to summer
あなたは泣きもせず、明日を待つ
You wait for tomorrow without even crying
少年少女たちが すれ違うことなく
The boys and girls, without ever passing each other
運命よ残酷だ、まま
Fate is cruel, just as it is
世界はこんなにも ひとつ、ふたつ、みっつ、よっつ
The world is so... one, two, three, four
いくつあるの
How many are there?
どれが正解なの？
Which one is the right answer?
世界はこんなにも 還る、還る、還る、還る
The world returns like this, back and back
目が解けて おかしくなりそうよ
My eyes are unravelling, I feel like I'm going crazy
ーあと一度だけー
-Just one more time-
世界はこんなにも 転がる、転がる、転がる、転がる
The world rolls like this, on and on
声にならない
It's beyond words
本当に私、叫んでしまったんだわ
I've really just ended up screaming
生きるために傷つけて確かめた
I hurt others just to live, and I confirmed it
私、今…
And now, I...
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
Rotate... Repeated...
不条理な生き方
An absurd way of living
…素晴らしき世界
...A wonderful world
イエスと言えば人間合格
Say "Yes" and you're a human qualification
笑えもっと　どんな顔だったっけ
Smile more, what kind of face was it again?
心のうちと鼓動
The heart within and its beat
非合法だ　聞かせて
It's illegal, let me hear it
素晴らしき世界
A wonderful world
ノーと言えば人間降格
Say "No" and you're a human demotion
素敵巧妙なシナリオだったっけ
Was it a wonderful, clever scenario?
終わりは突然に
The end comes suddenly
そして淡々と　過ぎて朽ちていく
And calmly, it passes and decays
くだらない日々は過ぎ　そう過ぎてゆく
Worthless days pass, yes, they pass by
そう決められたルールに
To the rules decided like that
そう従って　楽になって
Following them, getting easier
森に迷い込んでいたんだ
I was lost in the forest
非合法だ　聞かせて
It's illegal, let me hear it
素晴らしき世界
A wonderful world
イエスと答えて　人間合格
Answer "Yes" and you're a human qualification
神の愛は信じるものだけ
God's love is only for those who believe
罰を与えられてるんで
Because punishment is being given
そして淡々と　過ぎて朽ちていく
And calmly, it passes and decays
叶えたい夢を捨て　そう夢を見て
Throwing away the dreams I want to fulfill, yes, dreaming
そう決められたルールに
To the rules decided like that
そう従って　楽になって
Following them, getting easier
森に迷い込んでいくんだ
I'm getting lost in the forest
君は泣いた　アスファルトを破り咲いた
You cried, a flower that bloomed through the asphalt
花が笑いながら言った　花が言った
Said while laughing, the flower said
君は泣いた　アスファルトを破り咲いた
You cried, a flower that bloomed through the asphalt
花が笑いながら言った　花が言った
Said while laughing, the flower said
くだらない日々は過ぎ　そう過ぎてゆく
Worthless days pass, yes, they pass by
そう決められたルールに
To the rules decided like that
そう従って　楽になって
Following them, getting easier
森に迷い込んでいくんだ
I'm getting lost in the forest
君は泣いた　アスファルトを破り咲いた
You cried, a flower that bloomed through the asphalt
花が笑いながら言った　花が言った
Said while laughing, the flower said
夜も遅いけど　もっともっと盛り上がっていきましょう！
It's late at night, but let's get even more excited!
ヘイ！
Hey!
偽物ばかりすべて
Everything is just fakes
上辺で飾って誤魔化して
Decorating the surface and deceiving
何が正解かわかんないから
Because I don't know what's right
壊れていく
It's breaking down
いったい何が本当なんだっけ
What on earth was real?
期待しても裏切られてばかり
Even if I expect something, I'm only betrayed
いつも泣いてしまうよ
I always end up crying
こんな異常だらけの世界で
In a world full of abnormalities like this
存在意義探してるんだ
I'm searching for the meaning of my existence
絶望のないシナリオはどこですか
Where is the scenario without despair?
こんな異常だらけの世界へ
To this world full of abnormalities
存在意義探してるんだ
I'm searching for my reason for being
何を言われても
No matter what anyone says
満たされることないよ
I'll never be satisfied
虚像(Fake) だって
Even if it's a fake image
見慣れた景色さえも
Even the familiar scenery
空の色に染まってしまう
Becomes dyed in the color of the sky
何が正解か知らないから
Because I don't know what's correct
縛られてしまう
I'm bound
一体何に本気なんだっけ
What exactly was I serious about?
自問自答を繰り返して
Repeating self-questioning and self-answering
明日を夢見てる
Dreaming of tomorrow
こんなまがい物の世界は
This counterfeit world
自分を見失いそうだ
I'm about to lose myself
痛みなど感じないで
Without feeling any pain
生きていたい
I want to live
こんなまがい物の世界は
This counterfeit world
自分を見失いそうだ
I'm about to lose myself
助けてと叫んだら
If I shout for help
救いの手はありますか
Is there a saving hand?
虚像(Fake) だって
Even if it's a fake image
もう疲れてしまったよ
I'm already tired
何度でも
Any number of times
やり直せたらいいのに
If only I could start over
こんな異常だらけの世界へ
To this world full of abnormalities
存在意義探してるんだ
I'm searching for my reason for being
絶望のない自由な日は何処ですか
Where is the free day without despair?
こんな異常だらけの世界へ
To this world full of abnormalities
存在意義探してるんだ
I'm searching for my reason for being
何を言われても
No matter what anyone says
満たされることないよ
I'll never be satisfied
虚像(Fake) だって
Even if it's a fake image
全ては Fake
Everything is Fake
ありがとう！
Thank you!
皆さん、改めてまして
Everyone, once again
こんあずきー！
Kon-AZKi!
AZKi です！
It's AZKi!
いや皆さん、夜更かしですね。
Well everyone, you're staying up late.
夜遅い時間ですけれど、皆さん、盛り上がってますか？
It's a late hour, but everyone, are you getting hyped?
起きてますか？
Are you awake?
元気ですか？
Are you feeling good?
はい。えっとですね。今日は、
Yes. Um. Today,
YouTube Music Weekend スペシャルライブとしまして、
as a YouTube Music Weekend Special Live,
AZKi のライブをここで披露しております！イエーイ！
I am performing AZKi's live here! Yay!
はい。えっとですね、今日は、
Yes. Um, today,
あの普段応援してくれている開拓者のみんなはもちろんですね、
of course, the Pioneers who usually support me,
それ以外の人もきっと何かの縁で、きっと見てくれているかなと思うので、
but I think people other than that are also watching through some kind of connection,
AZKi のライブはこれだぞ！というところをですね、
so I want you to see that "This is AZKi's live!",
見ていただきたいなと思っておりますので、
so I want you to see that,
一緒にコメントとか盛り上げてくれると嬉しいです。よろしくお願いします！
so I'd be happy if you could help liven things up with comments and stuff. Please look forward to it!
ということで、3曲、お聴きいただきました。
With that, you've listened to three songs.
お水飲んでいいですか？
Can I have some water?
お水を、お水飲みますよ。
Water... I'm going to drink some water.
よいしょ。はい。
Heave-ho. Yes.
お水を補給したところで、次はですね、
Now that I've rehydrated, next,
あの曲を、あの曲を、歌いたいと思います。
I'm going to sing that song, that song.
はい。
Yes.
それでは聴いてください。
Now, please listen.
「Shiny Smily Story」
"Shiny Smily Story".
With the hands of light and destiny
Oh, we wish your shining dreams
We make that choice, with the fine voice
Oh yes, we know, just let it go
Shiny Smily Story English ver.
You're the one who set aside your smile
It was a dark and hopeless space
It was your shining eyes that caught me
Filled with countless starry dreams
Wanna know the surface and be burst enough,
just when the tune my heart beats up.
I wish I, I wish my, my dreams will come true.
The first page of my history.
Who's telling me to give it up?
There is a world in my hands now.
I will never be alone, no, no anymore.
We are the shiny smiley stars!
Put your hands up, what a planet of dreams,
give it all the energy.
Play your mind, now take my hand,
shout it out, our dream is on!
Access to my heart, you will see,
no regrets, my heart is so free.
We make a choice with different voice,
oh yes we know, just set and go.
From the top of the sky above,
my precious eyes with smiley days.
It's a life you have never seen before,
standing for you, come on and get it.
Do you remember what the love you gave,
it's always here with me I stay.
Every voice, every heart I get from you,
but now enough, I want it more.
Your precious smile is like a spell,
amazing thoughts that make me smile.
You will never see my tears, with it disappears,
'cause it's my shiny smiley life.
Put your hands up, what a planet of dreams,
one big story, let it just scream.
Together we can make it be,
a never ending story.
Every world is starting to stay,
feel the love and shiny smile.
We make a choice with different voice,
oh yes we know, just set and go.
When I'm sad, you give your rays,
your heart is so, I feel the touch.
Touch my skin and you will feel my guts,
whenever you need, there will be no fear.
This breeze will dry every tears,
look at my future shining glow.
Make everyone to know my shiny smile.
Put your hands up, what a planet stage,
this is me in my shiny space.
Tears of joy and grow happy days,
just as stars that we had just made.
Hold my hand to see our future,
please my dream come true for my life.
My shining stars, step by step, a miracle.
Put your hands up, what a planet of dreams,
give it all the energy.
Play your mind, now take my hand,
shout it out, our dream comes true.
Access to my heart, you will see,
no regrets, my heart is so free.
We make a choice with different voice,
oh yes we'll create a world.
一緒に歌ってね！
Sing along with me!
壊してなくなった壁は
The walls that were broken and gone,
いつかあったことも忘れて
I even forgot they once existed.
壊すためのその拳は
That fist meant for destroying,
何を作るの
what will it create?
離れた星の住人が
The inhabitants of distant stars,
わけも知らず
without even knowing why,
またぶつかり
are clashing
合っている
with each other again.
ステージのバックライトは
The stage backlights are
背中に感じるだけじゃない
not just something I feel on my back.
次に立つ誰かのために
For the sake of the next person standing here,
輝いている
they are shining.
今すぐ世界は
The world won't
変わらないけど
change right away, but
11年後の君に歌うよ
I'll sing for you 11 years from now.
今日も夜空は
Even though the night sky
こんなに冷たいのに
is so cold today,
この街の灯は
the lights of this city
いつも熱い
are always hot.
一人一人の
Because each and every person's
ストーリーが
story is
あふれているから
overflowing.
飛び出せ SHiNY STAGE!
Jump out, SHiNY STAGE!
届け未来へ！
Reach for the future!
届け未来的 Show Time!
Deliver this futuristic show time!
自信持ってもっと激しく遊べ My sister
Be confident and play even harder, my sister
今も Stage Tree 全部叶えていこう
Even now on Stage Tree, let's make it all come true
夢見る力が地上を照らせば
If the power of dreaming illuminates the earth
誰かの好きが繋がって So Miracle
Someone's "like" will connect, creating a miracle
またいつか花開くよ ソラサイクル
One day it will bloom again, Sora Cycle
ぼくら自分と世界の時間を混同しがちで
We tend to confuse our time with the world's time
世界が大人になってると勘違いして
Mistakenly thinking that the world has grown up
あるときループから放り出されて
One day, thrown out of the loop
変わり映えしない日々に戸惑う
And bewildered by the unchanging days
誰かの夢が連鎖してゆくのは
The chain of someone's dreams
自由を縛る鎖じゃなくて
Isn't a chain that binds your freedom
少しずつでもまだ見ぬ世界
Even if it's just bit by bit, a world yet unseen
見えたらいいよね
I hope we can see it
飛び出せ Say Hello!
Fly out, Say Hello!
響け宇宙的 Big Wave
Resonate, a cosmic Big Wave
瞳輝かせて君が好きさ My sister
Sparkling eyes, I love you, my sister
今も Stage Tree いつも全身全霊
Even now on Stage Tree, always with my whole soul
磁力線の向こう側目指して
Aiming for the other side of the magnetic field lines
一瞬の閃光が永遠になって Spark
A momentary flash becomes eternal, Spark
この世界を変えていくよ ソラサイクル
Changing this world, Sora Cycle
みんな、まだまだ盛り上がって行けますかー！
Everyone, can we keep getting even more hyped?!
ハイ！
Hai!
懐かしいことが心地いいとき
When nostalgic things feel comfortable
新しいことは辛いこと
New things are painful things
それでも新しい
Even so, I want to see
日が見たい 明日が見たい
a new day, I want to see tomorrow
飛び出せ Say Hello!
Fly out, Say Hello!
届け未来的 Show Time!
Deliver this futuristic show time!
自信持ってもっと激しく遊べ My sister
Be confident and play even harder, my sister
今も Stage Tree 全部叶えていこう
Even now on Stage Tree, let's make it all come true
夢見る力が地上を照らせば
If the power of dreaming illuminates the earth
誰かの好きが繋がって So Miracle
Someone's "like" will connect, creating a miracle
またいつか花開くよ ソラサイクル
One day it will bloom again, Sora Cycle
ぼくらの今が君を動かして
Our present moves you
またいつか花開くよ ソラサイクル
One day it will bloom again, Sora Cycle
みんな一緒に歌ってね！
Everyone, sing along!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
最後！
The last one!
少しずつ近づいているよ 夢に見たときめき
Getting closer bit by bit, the excitement I dreamed of
広がってく世界中に
Spreading throughout the world
みんなを笑顔にさせるきらめきを
a sparkle that brings a smile to everyone
一人じゃないんだ ライバルがいるから
I'm not alone, because I have rivals
競い合うことすら 楽しくなっちゃうんだよ
Even competing with each other becomes fun
見合って
Facing each other
未来へ走り出したら ファンタスティック
Running towards the future, fantastic
夢を咲かせて アワフューチャー
Let your dreams bloom, our future
一歩一歩踏み出して トップを目指そう
Taking it step by step, let's aim for the top
信じる力が心のハピネス
The power to believe is the happiness in my heart
全力で楽しもう それはいつかきっと
Let's enjoy it with all our might, surely someday it will be
大きな夢
a big dream
叶えるかな
I'll make it come true
Dreaming Days
答えもない道をゆく
Walking a path with no answers
誰も見たことのない世界
A world no one has ever seen
連れていくよ
I'll take you there
みんなのこと
all of you
覚悟はいいかな
Are you ready?
手を離さないで
Don't let go of my hand
一人じゃないよ
I'm not alone
君が見ているから
because you're watching
初めての挑戦中だ
In the middle of my first challenge
楽しくなっちゃうんだよ
It's getting to be fun
We Dreaming!
Yeah!
奇跡を巻き起こすんだ Believe
I'll make miracles happen, Believe
夢に近づいて My Story
Getting closer to my dreams, My Story
とても小さな蕾が花咲かせるまで
Until a very small bud blooms
挑戦し続けるんだ Believe
I'll keep on challenging, Believe
全力で飛び込もう
Let's dive in with all our might
ほんの少しだけの勇気が今
Just a little bit of courage now
僕らを変えるんだ Dreaming Days
Will change us, Dreaming Days
選んできた未来の選択肢
The choices for the future I've made
すべてがほら私を作った
Everything, you see, made me who I am
選ぶことのなかった中にさえ
Even among the things I didn't choose
大事な意味があったと気づいたよ
I realized there was an important meaning
涙を流した数がEmotion
The number of tears shed is Emotion
熱い鼓動がOverheat
Hot heartbeat is Overheat
本気だからこそ思える
I can feel this way precisely because I'm serious
トップになりたい
I want to be at the top
未来へ走り出したら Fantastic
If I start running towards the future, it's Fantastic
全力で楽しもう
Let's enjoy with all our might
それはいつかきっと大きな夢
That will surely one day be a big dream
叶えるかな
I'll make it come true
Dreaming Days Oh Yeah
走り続けていくんだ Greatest
I'll keep on running, Greatest
一人じゃ届かない高みへ
To heights I can't reach alone
Yeah!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ありがとう。
Thank you.
はい、ということで、
Alright, so,
AZKiお水タイム！
it's AZKi's water time!
お水、お水。
Water, water.
はい。
Alright.
みんなもお水を補給してもらって。
Everyone, please replenish your water too.
ふふっ。
(Laughs)
はい、ということでちょっとまたMCなんですけれども
Okay, so it's time for another MC segment,
ちょっとね、なんか、なんかこう、改まって、
but I wanted to take a moment
なんかちょっとみんなに、こういう場で、ちょっとお話、なんか、しようと思って
to formally talk to you all like this.
ちょっとね、最近ちょっと考えていることを、ここで、
I'd like to talk about some things I've been thinking about lately,
深夜の... 深夜のテンションでちょっとお話したいと、思っています。
with my... my late-night energy.
はい。
Yes.
えっと先日、えっと私の大好きな可不ちゃんのですね、
Um, the other day, after my dear KAFU-chan's...
あの不解不2のリビ・リビルディングか、が終わってから
'FUKAIFU 2 REBUILDING' ended,
えっと、そう、AZKiのライブとか、その、
I've been thinking about AZKi's lives and...
普段一緒に活動しているAZKiチーム의、なんかこう、良さってなんだろうなー、ということをですね、
...what makes the AZKi team I work with special.
とてもとても、とてもとても考えまして
I've been thinking about it a lot.
そう、めちゃくちゃ、あのね、話したりしてたんですけど。はい。
Yeah, I've been talking about it quite a bit. Yes.
なんか、どう、なんかこう、可不ちゃんのライブとかって、
I feel like KAFU-chan's lives have
すごくすごく、なんかこう、物語とか、
this incredible sense of story
なんかこう、圧倒的な、なんか、なんだろうな、世界観とか、なんかそういうのが、あると思っていて
and an overwhelming worldview, or something like that.
それがすごくAZKiは好きで、
I really love that,
なんかいつもね、もう、心を鷲掴みにされ、
and my heart is always gripped by it,
え、もうなんか、しばらく放心状態みたいな、ことがよくあるんですけど
and I often end up in a daze for a while afterward.
なんかまあ、AZKiチームで、まあ、なんかそういうの、
And I wondered if the AZKi team,
自分たちには、なんか、まあ、ない、というか、
well, if we lacked that,
まあ、ないかなーっていうことで、思ったりとか、
or if we were just trying to catch up to it.
まあ、それに、まあ追いつこうとなんかしたりとか
Or something like that.
なんかそういう、なんだろうな。自分たちが、こう...
Like, what is it? Our...
可不ちゃんは可不ちゃんの、可不ちゃんチームは可不ちゃんチームの良さがあって、
KAFU-chan and her team have their own unique strengths,
じゃあ、AZKiチーム、AZKiの良さってなんだろうなっていうのを
so I recently had another chance to think about
すごく、最近、また改めて、考えるきっかけを、頂いたなーと思っていて。
what makes the AZKi team and AZKi special.
そう、それでね、なんか、どう、どうなんだろうな。
Yeah, so, I wonder what it is.
AZKi、AZKi、AZKiって、なんだろうね。
What exactly is AZKi?
なんか、こう、なんかそれの、なんか劣化版というか...
Something like... well, like a degraded version of that...
...なんか、模倣でしか、なんかちょっと、なかったりとか...
...or just something like... a bit of an imitation...
...なんかね、実際そうやって思うところが、まあ、あるわけですよ。
...you know, there are actually times when I feel that way.
まあ、いろいろね、活動している中で、いろんなものを目に、して...
Well, while doing various activities and seeing various things...
...体験して、自分たちはどうだろう、って、結構振り返ることがあるんですけど...
...and experiencing them, I often look back and think, "how about us?" but...
でも、なんかそんな中で、まあ、こうやって開拓者のみんなが...
But, in the midst of all that, well, having all the Pioneers like this...
...AZKiのことを、なんでこう、なんで、なんでって言うと失礼かもしれないんですけど...
...supporting AZKi—saying "why" might be rude, but...
なんか、なんで応援してくれているんだろう、ということを考えましてですね...
...I've been thinking about why you all support me...
...考え、て...
...thinking about it...
まぁ、でもそこ、それってきっと...
Well, but that's probably...
あの、歌が好きだったりとか、こうやって、なんか普段話してる感じが、好きだったりとか...
...that you like my songs, or you like the way I usually talk...
...いろいろあると思うんですけど。
...I'm sure there are many reasons.
なんかこう、昔からね、まずっと一緒に歩いてくれているみんなは...
For those who have been walking with me for a long time...
...こう何だろうな、まあ、最初から比べるとめちゃくちゃに、変化したと思うんですよ。AZKiも。
...well, I think I've changed immensely since the beginning. AZKi has.
歴史を辿ると、いろんなことがあって、まあ、そういう、何だろうな、変化っていうのを...
Looking back at history, so many things happened, and that, well, kind of change...
...一緒にこうやって楽しんで、くれているのかな、というふうに思って...
...is something you've been enjoying with me, I think...
...思って、いまして。
...I've been thinking.
だからやっぱり、常にね...
That's why, after all, always...
...なんかこう、目標とか、なんかこう、新しい姿とか、挑戦とか、なんか変化し続け、ないといけないし...
...like, goals, or a new look, or challenges, I have to keep changing...
...まあ、だからね、こうやって新しい、衣装になってからもね、こう...
...and that's why, even after getting this new outfit, you know...
...あの応援し始めてくれた、開拓者のみんなは、いると思うんですけど...
...I'm sure there are Pioneers who started supporting me from then, but...
...えーと、そういう、なんかその、いろんな場面でこうやってAZKiに出会ってくれた開拓者のみんなと...
...um, with all the Pioneers who have met AZKi in various situations like that...
...これからも、えーと、一緒に変化っていうのを、なんか楽しんでいきたいなと、思っています。
...I want to continue enjoying this "change" together from now on.
なんか、ね、こう、ライブを重ねるごとにね、なんかその日、歌う、曲はさ...
You know, with every live performance, the songs I sing that day...
...なんかちょっと、違ったりとか、なんかその日、その日で、ライブも、なんか何だろうな...
...are a bit different, and from day to day, the live shows are, what can I say...
...作り上げる、ものが、違ったりするので。
...the things we create are different.
まあそういう、なんか日々の、成長とかも、なんか楽しんでもらえたら、いいなって、思っています。
So, those kinds of daily growths... are things I hope you can enjoy too.
うんと、あと、私たちはね、まあこの、この、ね、世界で、まあ今大変で、いろんなことが、起こっていると思うんですけど...
And, also, we are, well, in this world, and things are tough now, so many things are happening...
まあ、あの、世の中、なんかこう楽しいこととか、まあ、寂しいこととか...
Well, you know, in the world, there are fun things, and well, lonely things...
...なんか変わってしまってどうしようもないこととか、いろいろ、いろいろみんな、いろんな状況で...
...things that have changed and can't be helped, and everyone is in various situations...
...大変だったり、すると思うんですけど。
...and it must be tough, I think.
まあ、その、なんか、そういったこととかを、なんか元気づけられたりとか、AZKiが元気づけられたりとか...
Well, um, through things like that, I hope I can cheer you up, or AZKi gets cheered up...
...まあちゃんと一つ一つ、えーと、しっかり向き合って、なんかこう...
...and facing each thing properly, um, and like...
...AZKiはここにいたんだぞ、っていう、あの生きた証を、刻んでいこう、と...
...I'll leave a mark, a proof of life that "AZKi was here," and...
...いうことが、なんか、とても、大事なんだなと、思っています。
...that's something I think is very important.
えー、だからこそ、こうやって開拓者のみんなの、なんか一つ一つのコメントとか...
That's exactly why, having each of the Pioneers' comments like this...
...えーと、そういうのを大事にして、これからも頑張っていきたいと、思っています。
...um, I want to cherish those and keep doing my best from now on.
まあ、この世界はね、うーん、ノンフィクション。今日のライブタイトルにもありますけど...
Well, this world is, hmm, Non-Fiction. As in the title of today's live...
ノンフィクションです。えーと、厳しいこともたくさんあるんですけど...
It's Non-Fiction. Um, there are many harsh things, but...
今、AZKiが歌っていて、えー、開拓者のみんなが応援してくれて、場所や、時間をこうやって飛び越えて...
Right now, AZKi is singing, and all the Pioneers are supporting me, and leaping across place and time like this...
...いろんな気持ちを、まあ共、共有か、共有することができるっていうのは、とってもとっても、かけがえのないことだと思います。
...to share, being able to share various feelings is something I think is very, very irreplaceable.
ひとつひとつの出来事を大切に、うーん、5年後、10年後...
Cherishing each event, hmm, 5 years, 10 years later...
...10年後、もっともっと、その先も、なんかこういうことがあったな、って、思い出せる...
...10 years later, even further beyond that, I hope we can remember that things like this happened...
...なんか、こう、キラキラ、キラキラした、思い出を、たくさん作っていこうね。
...let's make lots of sparkling, sparkling memories, okay?
いこうね、いこうね、はい。えーと、ちょっと長々とお話ししたんですけれども...
Let's do it, let's do it, yes. Um, I've talked for quite a while, but...
...そんな、思いを込めて、えー、すべての才能ある命に、歌いたいと、思います。
...with those feelings in mind, um, I'd like to sing to all talented lives.
聴いてください。「いのち」。
Please listen. "Inochi".
息をしている
Breathing
君は生きている
You are alive
当然のことだね 誰も疑わないの
It's only natural, no one doubts it
息をしている
Breathing
ように見えている
Or so it seems
生の裏側 私にとっての何か
The flip side of life, what it means to me
鼓動がトクトクしている
My heart is beating fast
叩かれても腐らずに
Even if I'm criticized, I won't give up
ここで歌うよ
I'll sing here
ボタンひとつの気持ち
The feeling of a single button
最後まで私のこと覚えててくれるの？
Will you remember me until the end?
消えてしまいそうなの
It seems like I'm about to disappear
分かってよ分かってよ ねえ
Understand me, understand me, hey
淡々と踊るの
Dancing indifferently
恋しさは違うでしょ
Longing is different, right?
君が忘れちゃったら
If you forget me
私は痛くなるの
I'll start to feel the pain
命のような夢を見てるよ
I'm dreaming a dream like life itself
またね バイバイ
See you again, bye-bye
息をしている
I am breathing
だから生きてる
That's why I'm living
自己証明を欲しがって 欲しがっているんだ
I'm longing for, longing for self-proof
音が止まって
The sound stops
動かなくなって
And I stop moving
そんな私を君は笑ってくれるかな
I wonder if you'll laugh at me then
鼓動がトクトクしている
My heart is beating fast
嫌われても腐らずに
Even if I'm hated, I won't give up
ここで歌うよ
I'll sing here
気分次第な命
Life that depends on the mood
最後まで私のこと見届けてくれるの？
Will you watch over me until the very end?
褪めてしまいそうなの
It seems like I'm about to fade away
分かってよ分かってよ ねえ
Understand me, understand me, hey
声が聞こえるんだよ
I can hear your voice
塩辛い涙が出ちゃうほど
So much that salty tears flow out
君が忘れちゃったら
If you forget me
私は痛くなるの
I'll start to feel the pain
命のような夢を見てるよ
I'm dreaming a dream like life itself
またね バイバイ
See you again, bye-bye
塞ぎ込んだあの日を
That day when I was feeling down
軽く弄らないで 止めて
Don't tease me about it lightly, stop it
それが生きる糧になるから
Because that becomes my strength to live
大丈夫
It's okay
ずっと私は歌い続けるから
Because I'll keep singing forever
最後まで私は生きてるか分からないけど
I don't know if I'll be alive until the end, but
君がくれた言葉は確かに残ってる
The words you gave me certainly remain
最後まで私のこと覚えててくれるの？
Will you remember me until the end?
いつ死んでしまうかなんて 分かんない分かんないよ ねえ
I don't know, I don't know when I'll die, hey
痛いくらい気持ちがシンクロする時もあるけど
There are times when our feelings synchronize so much it hurts
君が忘れちゃったら
If you forget me
私は痛くなるの
I'll start to feel the pain
命のような夢を見てるよ
I'm dreaming a dream like life itself
またね バイバイ
See you again, bye-bye
ちいさななるが決めたこと
What the little one decided
あの日選んで君が道は間違いだったんだって 過去恨んでみても
Even if you regret the past, thinking the path you chose that day was a mistake
土砂降りの雨が責めたって
Even if the downpouring rain blames you
俯いた顔は
With a downcast face
ひどく弱いことに気づいたら
Once I realized how terribly weak I was
この先には叶えたいことや夢があるから
Because ahead of me, there are dreams and things I want to achieve
目を逸らさないように
So that I don't look away
正解はない 誰だって一人で
There's no right answer; everyone's alone
思うまま始まっていく この物語
This story begins just as we wish
今をただ走って
Just running through the present
季節を駆け巡って
Running through the seasons
見えない暗闇の中で
In the unseen darkness
痛みだってあるよ
There will be pain
戸惑いだってあるよ
There will be confusion
それでもここで生きていくと 決めたんだ
Even so, I've decided to live right here
決めたから
Because I've decided
前を向いて
I'll look forward
生き方を誰が決めていて
Who decides how we should live?
本当はそうじゃなかったとか今更嘆いたって
It's too late to lament that it wasn't really like that
味方もヒーローも現れなくて
No allies or heroes appear
喧騒の中でどこか彷徨いかけていたんだ
I was about to wander off somewhere in the bustle
この先には奏でたい音や歌があるから
Because ahead of me, there are sounds and songs I want to play
耳を澄ますように
I'll listen closely
間違いはない 誰だって一人で
There's no mistake; everyone's alone
綴り綴られていく この物語
This story is being written and woven
過去今未来が
Past, present, and future
あなたを駆け巡って
Run through you
理想と現実の中で
In between ideal and reality
泣きたくもなるよ
Sometimes I want to cry
諦めたくなるよ
Sometimes I want to give up
それでもここで生きていくと 決めたんだ
Even so, I've decided to live right here
決めたから
Because I've decided
走り出すよ
I'll start running
生まれ変わっても この話をしよう
Even if I'm reborn, let's tell this story
この人生で良かったと
Saying that I'm glad I had this life
痛みは力に
Pain into strength
戸惑いは期待に
Confusion into expectation
そうしてここで生きていくと
And so, I'll live right here
今をただ走って
Just running through the present
季節を駆け巡って
Running through the seasons
見えない暗闇の中で
In the unseen darkness
痛みだってあるよ
There will be pain
戸惑いだってあるよ
There will be confusion
それでもここで生きていくと 決めたんだ
Even so, I've decided to live right here
決めたから
Because I've decided
前を向いて
I'll look forward
ありがとう。
Thank you.
はい、ということでお送りしたのは
Yes, and so those songs were
「命」と「小さな心が決めたこと」でした。
'Life' and 'What a Small Heart Decided'.
なんと、なんとね、このセカンドの衣装に
And would you look at that, into this second outfit,
チェンジして歌わせていただきました。
I changed and performed for you.
はい、ということで早いものでラスト3曲ということで、
Yes, and so, time flies, and we're down to the last three songs.
ここからはノンストップで行きたいと思っているので、
From here, I'd like to go non-stop,
MCはこれで最後になります。
so this will be the last MC section.
その前にお水を飲もう。お水、お水。
Before that, let me drink some water. Water, water.
ふあ〜！
Phew!
時空を超えた映像、
Footage that transcended spacetime...
時空を超えてお水を飲んできました。
I've come back from drinking water across spacetime.
はい、ということでサード…サード衣装にチェンジしまして、
Yes, and so, I've changed into my third... third outfit,
ラスト3曲をお届けしたいと思います。
and I'd like to perform the last three songs.
お話しした通りなんですけど...
As I mentioned...
えっと、今日はこのスペシャルライブ
NON FiCTiONということで...
Um, today is this special live,
"NON FiCTiON"...
ノンフィクションなこの世界で、えー、
変化し続けることを大切にしていきたいし...
In this non-fiction world, I want to
value continuing to change...
こういうね、非日常のこういうライブ、
あ、もちろん...
This kind of extraordinary live show, and of course...
ま、普段やっているAZKiんちの日常の配信でも、
どんどん変化していけるようになりたいと思います！
even in my usual daily streams at "AZKi-nchi",
I want to be able to keep changing more and more!
えー、開拓者のみんなと一緒に
足跡を残していきたいと思っています！
I want to continue leaving footprints
together with all you Pioneers!
だからこれからも一緒に歩いていこうね！
So let's keep walking together from now on, okay?
それでは聞いてください。in this world。
Now, please listen. "in this world."
綻ぶ言葉を見失ってる
I'm losing sight of the words that bloom
空が涙を降らせていたんだ
The sky was letting tears fall
誰のために 何のために
For whom? For what purpose?
これが運命だと言うの？
Is this what you call destiny?
嘘が街を包み込んでいる
Lies are enveloping the city
鳥が飛べずに声を上げていた
The birds, unable to fly, were raising their voices
たった一つの存在を灯す
Lighting up a single existence
この場所で君を待ってる
I'm waiting for you in this place
世界はとても苦しそうでした
The world seemed very painful
私に何ができるというの？
What can I possibly do?
歌うことが正しいかなんて
Whether singing is the right thing to do...
確かなのは君がいたから
What's certain is that because you were here
私はここにいるの
I am here
何回何十回だって
No matter how many times
君と出会うから
Because I'll meet you
夜が明けていく光が降り注ぎ
The night breaks into dawn, light pouring down
喜び悲しみを抱え前を向く
Embracing joy and sorrow, looking forward
君と生きてくここでこの場所で
I'll live with you here, in this place
それが私の世界だ
That is my world
その一秒一瞬が煌めく yeah
Every second, every moment shines, yeah
過去が道を壊したとしても
Even if the past destroyed the path
夢が街を食らい尽くそうとしても
Even if dreams are about to devour the city
大丈夫だからそばにいるよ
It's okay, because I'm by your side
君に笑ってほしいんだ
I want you to smile
生まれた意味を探しているの
I'm searching for the meaning of being born
転んでもただ走り続けていく
Even if I fall, I'll just keep on running
今を信じて明日を描いた
Believing in the now, I drew tomorrow
心が叫びたがってる
My heart wants to shout
タイムマシンに乗ってさ
別の未来を選ぶことが出来たなら
If I could have taken a time machine
and chosen a different future
君のいない世界を創造する？
そんな世界は想像できない
Would I create a world without you?
I can't imagine such a world.
君に届きますように
この声がこの歌が
May it reach you, this voice, this song
何回何十回だって君を選ぶから
Because no matter how many times, I'll choose you
夜が滲んでいく地平の彼方へ
The night blurs toward the horizon
響く呼吸の音を確かに感じた
I clearly felt the sound of breathing echoing
始めよう君とこの未来を
Let's begin, this future with you
繋いだ手を離さないで
Don't let go of our joined hands
大きな声で名前を呼んで
Call my name with a loud voice
奇跡を駆け抜けて
Running through miracles
どこまでも行けるよ
We can go anywhere
ここからもう一度 君と私で始めよう
Let's start once more from here, you and me
無限の中に生まれた物語を 君と歩いていく
Walking with you through the story
born in infinity
この世界が悲しみに溢れたとしても
Even if this world is overflowing with sadness
私は歌を歌い続けていく
I will continue to sing my song
君と生きてくここでこの場所で
I'll live with you here, in this place
それが私の世界だ
That is my world
その一秒一瞬が煌めく yeah
Every second, every moment shines, yeah
傷つき涙を流す君が 幸せだと思える世界へ
To a world where you, hurt and crying,
can feel happy
光になり
To become light
増すように
And grow stronger
願いを込め歌う
I sing with my wish
この扉の向こう側が 未開の可能性なら
If what lies beyond this door is an unexplored possibility
今を動かせる
I can move the present
暗闇を手探りで 不安と焦燥の中
Groping through the darkness, amidst anxiety and impatience
こぼれる光を見た
I saw the overflowing light
手を伸ばして
Reaching out my hand
この先は君のものだから
Because the path ahead belongs to you
時を超えて
Transcending time
繋がるよ 心が今
Our hearts are connected now
創造するのは私のストーリー
Creating my own story
声を聞かせて キミを知りたいから
Let me hear your voice, because I want to know you
輝かせよう 新しい世界
Let's make it shine, this new world
生まれた意味を見つけるのさ
I'll find the meaning of being born
全てが始まるこの場所で
In this place where everything begins
声が枯れるまで叫んで
Screaming until my voice gives out
言葉に傷つけられ 涙がこぼれるのは
When words hurt and tears fall
弱さゆえじゃないよ
It's not because of weakness
響きはここにあるから 掻き消されちゃだめなんだ
Because the resonance is here, you mustn't let it be drowned out
君は君のままでいい
It's okay to just be yourself
声をあげて
Raising our voices
私たちの歌は壊れない
Our song will never break
何度だって
No matter how many times
伝えるよ この想い今
I'll convey these feelings now
共鳴するのは私のストーリー
Resonating is my story
名前を呼んで そばにいるから
Call my name, because I'm right by your side
音を奏でよう 新しい世界
Let's play the music, this new world
キミに出会う為に生きていくんだ
I live on just to meet you
この場所が奇跡だから
Because this place is a miracle
リアルを超えて 繋ぐよ
Beyond reality, I'll connect us
さあ
Come on
微睡に落ちて
Falling into a slumber
やがて光が世界を照らすよ
Soon, the light will illuminate the world
君と出会えたこと 意味を見つけたのさ
Meeting you, I found the meaning
共に分かち合って生きたい
I want to live sharing it with you
創造するのは私のストーリー
Creating my own story
声を聞かせて キミを知りたいから
Let me hear your voice, because I want to know you
開拓するの 新しい世界
I'll blaze a trail, this new world
嘘じゃないんだ キミとのストーリー
It's not a lie, our story
全てが始まるこの場所で
In this place where everything begins
歌を歌い続けるよ
I'll keep on singing my song
みんな最後の曲です。一緒に！
Everyone, this is the last song. Together!
一緒に手振ってね！
Wave your hands together!
見せてあげたいな
I want to show you
私が見てきた
the many sights
たくさんの景色
that I've seen.
声に紡がれた街は
The city spun in voices
変わることを恐れてた
was afraid of change.
存在から連なる
Stemming from existence,
これまでの旅路の意味は
the meaning of our journey so far is...
君が数える未来
The future you count,
私が数えた過去
the past I counted.
溢れた数字 問いかけて
Question the overflowing numbers.
手振ってね
Wave your hands!
ねえ ここだって君が笑って
Hey, even here you're laughing,
君が歌った軌跡の途中
in the middle of the locus you sang.
辿り着いた未来の意味は
Even if we don't understand
分からなくても
the meaning of the future we reached,
この声だって この音だって
this voice, and this sound too,
今の君の存在証明
are the proof of your existence now.
当たり前の価値が変わる
The common values change
君の世界
in your world.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
君は気づくはず
You should notice
不安のありかに
where the anxiety lies,
いのちの痛みに
the pain of life.
声に出せない恐れも
Even the fears you can't voice,
生きている君のことを
about you being alive.
後悔とか 滲むの
Regrets and such, they blur.
これまでを認めてあげよう
Let's acknowledge everything so far.
世界も不世界も
The world, the non-world,
偽物も本物も
the fake, the real.
見つけた想いがこの世界
The feelings we found are this world.
みんなで！
Everyone together!
ねえ ここだって君が聞いて
Hey, even here you're listening.
不安の先は今は教えないよ
I won't tell you what's beyond the anxiety yet.
辿り着く君の手足で
With your own hands and feet arriving,
確かめるんだ
you'll confirm it.
この時だって この場所だって
This time, and this place too,
未来の君の存在理由
are the reason for your future existence.
当たり前の価値を思う
Thinking of the common values
私の世界
in my world.
今は旅路の荒野立つ
Standing in the wilderness of the journey now,
君の背を
your back...
光の波が次の座標へと
The waves of light to the next coordinates...
開いた大地に次の芽が
In the opened earth, the next sprouts
強く伸び
grow strongly.
約束しようよ この先で
Let's make a promise, beyond this point.
ねえ ここだって君が笑って
Hey, even here you're laughing,
君が歌った軌跡の途中
in the middle of the locus you sang.
辿り着いた未来の意味を 見つけに行くよ
I'm going to find the meaning of the future we reached.
この声だって この音だって
This voice, and this sound too,
次の世界に続いてゆくんだ
will continue on to the next world.
当たり前の価値を駆ける
Running through common values,
僕らの世界
our world.
ラララ...
La la la...
今の先へ きっとそこが フロンティアローカス
Beyond the present, surely that is the Frontier Locus.
みんなありがとう！
Thank you everyone!
ありがとうございました！AZKiでしたー！
Thank you very much! This was AZKi!